University of Connecticut
© 2005 University of Connecticut
University of Connecticut, Building Names Committee Records.
1963-1976.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Resaerch Center.
University of Connecticut. Building Names Committee.
.5 linear feet.
Committee materials pertaining to the naming of University buildings.
MSS19970082
History
A resolution passed at the meeting of the University of Connecticut Board of Trustees on 20 February 1963 stated “That it is the policy of this Board to authorize the naming of University buildings or parts thereof in the future in the honor of certain individuals under” general conditions further described in the resolution. Within the year, President Homer Babbidge established a “faculty committee to study the matter of appropriate names for some of the University buildings which at present are not named in honor of any specific person.”
Chair of the Committee
1963-1974 Albert Van Dusen
1974-1975 David Ivry
1976 Josephine Dolan
The Committee made recommendations for the naming of new buildings, usually University of Connecticut scholars associated with the academic discipline to be housed in the building, or after Connecticut residents of note. The Committee also did research on existing building names and compiled lists of names for future use. Recommendations were made by the Committee to the President, who, in turn, would present them to the Board of Trustees for approval.
Scope and Content
The collection contains administrative files, reports, memoranda, notes on the history of named buildings and correspondence dating from the creation of the committee in 1963-1964 to the change in chair in 1976. The files end with the chairmanship of Dean Dolan (School of Nursing). It is unknown how much longer the committee continued to operate after 1976.
The majority of the buildings considered were dormitories, although some academic buildings (Psychology) are mentioned. Only one regional campus building (Waterbury) is mentioned in the files.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Organizations:
University of Connecticut--Administration.; University of Connecticut--Buildings, structures, etc.
Places:
Storrs (Conn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.
Document Types:
Administrative Records.
Occupations:
Universities.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
Unknown.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Records, 1963-1976
  - Who's Who and Who Was Who (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - 1963-1965 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - 1966 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - 1967 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - 1968 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - 1969 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - 1970 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - 1971 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - 1972 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - 1973 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - 1974 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - 1975 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
  - 1976 (Box 1:, Folder 13)